if you hear that cous Takuya kind of
model is shot people at the mall it was
me
I guess we should start with the name
huh
that's my name I grew up named kisaki
economist yeah in Georgia now my first
job was on a construction site so I got
a whole lot I watch your own them
two-by-fours down there Kawasaki Econo
Lodge sweep that house out Suzuki
snuffleupagus I've heard them all man
kabuki metropolis karaoke streptococcus
those are all real names are weird I
have a buddy has the same name as
someone who snapped and shot a bunch of
people at the malls now he has that
association with his name see I will
never have that problem if you hear that
kiss tacky a condom Appa was shot people
at the mall it was me it's nice I get to
control that I'm a married man I've been
married four years now we know the odds
right 50% of marriages end in divorce
and the other half end in death
so we know going in it's not gonna end
well
we're hurting for death
ah honey I hope this ends in the debt I
hope one of us dies the other ones
nearby and sad that's how we know we won
I was a divorce lawyer my slogan would
be it's the only way to get out of this
alive love my wife she's so completely
obsessed with unplugging the toaster
which we've never even heard of
apparently it's a fire hazard she's
yelling at me from the other room unplug
the toast you're gonna burn the place
down
like I can't even burn the toast unless
I push it down twice a toaster is a
self-contained metal box on a stone slab
might be this is the hole safest thing
in the whole place if a toaster breaks
on the on position the whole day you're
at work what would happen it would just
gently warm the area immediately around
the toaster like honey the two wooden
spoons are a bigger fire hazard there
could be an earthquake and they might
rub against each other
unplug the toaster it's dangerous
meanwhile she's lighting a candle
underneath the curtain she's setting a
curling iron to the newspaper like honey
them it's yeah the butter next to the
toaster is a bigger hazard to our lives
right
generations of economy pal I've been
dropping dead from heart disease since
the beginning of time no one's ever died
from a runaway toaster fire have you
ever even heard of one you got to work
your friends all covered in black char
what happened dude really another
toaster fire tough month the other thing
my wife does it drives me bananas I will
ask her where she wants to eat and she
will say to me oh I don't know you pick
yeah you're familiar
then I pick then she winces and says
could we not go there yeah
we cannot go there in fact here's the
magic of communication we can go to
exactly the place that you want to go
all you have to do is say what it is why
are we playing a crazy game right now
I'm hungry then we got a marriage
license also weird phrase license
implies that if you're bad at they could
take it away dude Ernie went to New
Orleans with a bunch of guy friends how
was that trip it was awesome but I did
get three points on my marriage license
so gonna have to stay in the slow lane
for a little while oh it's Italian from
New Jersey the rumor about the temper is
true here's something I've never had to
say to my beautiful bride ever what is
it honey you can tell me now when she's
mad it's not a secret 20 years ago I was
dating a vanilla white girl she would
give me the silent treatment and I hated
it so much and now sounds pretty good
I miss it now I think she was messing
with me really you're mad but you're not
gonna top deal I'm gonna watch the game
let me know when you're done being mad
woe is me
you got me I've also been trying to
convince my wife for about five years
now that I do not snore in order to ruin
her life like babe I didn't even know it
was happening and see what can we have
to tell me about it which by the way how
is that a net gain for the team I'm
asleep you're awake you wake me up
now we're both awake why is this better
I don't understand next time leave cut
out the middleman leave the happy
sleeping guy you sleep on the couch
we'll talk about tomorrow well you guys
clapping alright one night we're talking
about snoring I know what if you were
deaf my story be a problem then she goes
No okay so we've established that you're
hearing is the problem should I just get
my stuff and go to the couch now yeah
but I love her man I love her so much it
scares me I said to a friend of mine and
then had to think about it what's scary
about love it's so fun it's so we I
think there's a fear in love I think
when you're really in love there's a
vulnerability you're afraid that it's
gonna someday not be right she could die
we run off with another dude I would be
devastated and that was thinking if she
died around with another dude either way
my day-to-day life after that'd be
pretty much the same but I think it
would be easier for me emotionally if
she died
right it's weirdly true because if she
leads me for somebody else and I wasn't
enough I was crabby in the morning I
wasn't emotionally available it wasn't
intellectually stimulating I was I was a
drag somehow whatever some terrible
painful truth but hit by a bus not my
fault it's not on me it's almost an it's
an easier next 30 years for me I know
I'm not well I can provide a compliment
to my wife give me a great compliment
one night and I am ruined it feels so
bad of it she said to me you're the
sexiest man alive which is ridiculous
compliment oh it's not even a little bit
true but it's a nice thing to say to a
person I should have said thanks you
know what I went with
alive
why you gotta winnowing down the people
who are alive you got something for
Patrick Swayze or something yeah told
you I ruined it too soon
we can go back further if you want to
ruin Capote I don't know if we go back
further as paper ham Lincoln does it get
funnier if you go someone not so recent
as a Greek I was excited to see this set
by the way yeah for a lot of Americans
an octopus is like scary 20,000 Leagues
Under the Sea or something but to agree
it's like hey dinner all right excellent
we were Greece a few years ago we saw
there's an airline from Cyprus called
Icarus err number Icarus he didn't
finish his flight
dick Chris wanted to fly to the Sun his
dad's like that's not a very good idea
he's like screw you I'm paraphrasing and
he built some wings out of wax and
feathers and he flew to the Sun and as
he got close they melted and he fell to
his death and it's a parable about
listening to your dad at least that's
the way my dad told me the story when
the people of Cyprus started up an
airline they thought well what's a good
story to inspire air travel hmm
Hindenburg's been taken let's go with
Icarus Icarus err it's better than
Oedipus err I guess I mean that's that's
a terrible flight okay Greek mythology
who's with me
seven of you enjoy Greek mythology
[Music]
we got a kid Oh a nine-year-old daughter
awesome kid yeah you followed the math
right four-year-old marriage nine year
old kid
yeah there's a lot more to that story
but the kids been fun in every face
would chew his one chin poop for three
days in a row and her mother was
freaking out like what are you freaking
out about is like a dream come true our
baby doesn't poop we win this kids like
a seedless watermelon
we got a boobless dog we're gonna the
perfect family when she was three we're
in Australia for a comedy festival when
she learned about crosswalks it's very
easy on us John here's a red man and a
green man and we learned the whole thing
and we come back to New York where we
live and there's a white man and an
orange hand which makes no sense but I
never even thought about it until I had
to explain it to a new person you know
cut to again totally true busy New York
City street corner people everywhere
loud three year old dad we have to wait
for the white man
yeah let's use our inside voice
for this conversation yes Sonny we have
to wait for the white man he decides
everything let's see what the white man
has to say and having a kid exposes your
other kids which is also challenging I
was on a park bench watching your play
one day I don't know I guess my belly
was sticking out a little boy I've never
seen runs up points at me and goes you
look like you have a baby in your tummy
and he runs away it's like what that kid
had no idea the emotional toll he left
behind that was a long bike ride that
night I can tell you that to the
hospital to make sure he was okay
she's a great kid she's expensive to get
to hang out with we had to survive a
custody battle oh my goodness it's crazy
it's so dumb I'm embarrassed it's part
of our story the lawyer was five hundred
dollars an hour does that seem like a
fair price to talk to a human I live in
New York if I'd be more than it should
be that's how New York is but that hurt
my feelings
it's like $500 is there a lobster sir
hang gliding lessons and a root canal
what's happening in this hour according
to my budget we have to resolve this in
30 minutes talk fast
chop-chop it's crazy and you can't get
your head around how much it costs
because they charge you for everything
they hate to write an email to the judge
they have a meeting with the other
lawyers that write up a thing they file
a motion they talk to you they go back
and this goes on for days and weeks and
months in a year for all the money we
spent we could have had two kids each
got one
that's a cleaner break there all right
anybody you got the long straw go say
goodbye to mom hug your brother it's
gonna be a tough road for that kid it's
crazy it's not even socially responsible
to spend money like that you could save
children in Africa for 60 cents a day if
we just stop fighting over one little
white girl we could save all of the
children of Africa but then of course I
would get to know and love the children
of Africa and she would try to keep me
from seeing them back to square one you
could laugh about my pain it's fun the
one good thing that came from it it
broke me from being cheap I don't care
how much things cost anymore my wife
went to go see Billy Joel at Madison
Square Garden she's like ah tickets are
150 bucks each I'm like well we spent a
hundred thousand to see a nine-year-old
she doesn't know any of our favorite
socks
she kind of sucks on the piano let's go
see Billy he was great
one of her mother's brilliant ideas
during the negotiation process was that
we should get a life insurance policy
with the other parent as the beneficiary
I'm not paying for the bounty on my own
head nor do I need to be tempted in the
other direction if she dies they're
gonna come talk to me first
and they should
I don't need a pot of gold at the end of
that daydream well my problems would be
over immediately and again a million
dollars it'd be irresponsible not to
consider that and I'm sure as a guy in
the world I'd advantages big and small
some of which I wasn't even aware of my
whole life just from being a guy but
when you're a guy in a custody battle
you are way behind before you can start
because culturally we think women are
better at raising children than men and
why have you looked around the world
people suck and women raised almost all
of us
come on that is a fun fun point don't
worry I'll walk it back
[Music]
unbalanced as a generalization are women
better at raising children than men yes
of course it's not even close the gap is
so large think about how low the
standards are for fathers in this
country to be dad of the year all you
gotta do is not drink during the day
it's a good father at least sober till
dinner
what are you offering the man it's crazy
so we hadn't what they've about half the
time which we could have done on a
napkin in a diner for free two years
it's maddening it's crazy
and I wish we had her all the time I
think she'd be better off and we'd love
that kid the good news is there's a
silver lining I get a break hey I get to
come talk to you guys for a few days I
get to go home be super debt I don't
have that thousand-yard stare the way
sometimes parents do when they're with
their kids all the time let's face it
kids are a little bit like Las Vegas
follow me on this when you get to Las
Vegas you're like I love Las Vegas so
much and then three days later you're
like I gotta get the hell out of Vegas
it's true right sumit dad half the time
can we do marriage half the time - I
think it'd be Elijah be married if it
was every other weekend and Wednesday
night Oh it'll be too honey but it's not
our weekend I'll see you on Wednesday
we just went to a wedding here's a
question why don't we give gifts to
people getting married people getting
married are in love I don't need things
to be happy we should give gifts to
people getting a divorce because when
you're alone crying in a studio
apartment that's would be good have a
really nice toaster I've been there
sometimes toast is the highlight of your
day things get really sad just bring
that thing into the tub with you that's
when you want to unplug the toaster
that's a very dangerous toaster
situation that I'll agree with some of
our traditions happen at the wrong times
obviously the bachelor party should
happen after the divorce now you're a
bachelor I enjoy that side of life
hanging with drunks and strippers that's
no way to prepare for marriage the
bridal shower that's a weird tradition
you hang around and give the bride sexy
underwear first of all you got this guy
you need sexy underwear show up naked
that's all we care about anyway besides
you're embarking on a journey it's gonna
be hard you got to get along with
another human being an intimate way for
a long period of time the bridal shower
should be a pet talk about lowering your
expectations
he knows I'm right so our traditions
happen at the wrong times Catholics
Confirmation 13 this evil young anybody
else the greatest thinkers and
philosophers since the beginning of time
have been trying to figure out whether
or not there's a God let's ask the kid
with the braces in the acne what he
thinks you can't ask a child a question
like that I gotta find a grown-up all
right man you're 63 none of your dreams
came true
you're upside down your house and your
wife can't stand to hear you breathe how
do you feel about God that's a more
interesting conversation some of our
traditions are weird man
even the luhan's like a housewarming
gift I just got to the neighborhood
you're bringing me a pie
I can't bake a pie you're proving you're
a better homemaker than I am on day one
slow down
you get to bring your genius
homeschooled kid over to obviously
that's a joke no homeschooled kid is a
genius
so hit close to home Utah
some traditions are weird I like the
tradition of serving drinks to people on
airplanes I fly that's nice but what
about the people on the bus because if
you're on the bus things are not going
well you could use a trip give that man
a drink he's on greyhound oh I took
Greyhound a few times in the old days
it's just a bunch of people I don't have
a car or a friend with a car
scouts from the Springer Show were there
looking for talent
the bus is slow and they have the Gaul
named after a racing dog especial be
called crippled poodle Chihuahua with
rickets may be the strangest tradition
in all of American culture
the retirement party really you're
giving me a gold watch today the first
thing in my whole life that I don't care
what time it is I'm never gonna look at
a watch again watch me trade this in for
a hammock I would love to be retired
that's something an old guy says right
looking forward to it now here's how I'm
getting older now when I see a beautiful
teenage girl I think to myself wow I bet
she's got a hot mom it's funny I want to
see the mother now I didn't know that
was the next phase of life
does that continue of in some way
where's granny I want to see three
generations of this magic let's go
trying to eat better now that I'm a
grown-up be enjoying the rice cakes as
much as I why they come with a twist tie
are they worried they're gonna go stale
these are terrible yes they're fresh
a price cake is it tastes like a star
like you punched a circle out of his
styrofoam coolers first time I had rice
cakes I thought there was a mixup at the
factory well obviously these are the
packing materials that the cakes usually
come in keep them moist and delicious
how'd you screw up rice and cake those
are both good things rice pudding is
awesome carrot cake fantastic rice cake
kill yourself a urinal cake is better
than a rice cake please say you have low
expectations you'll be fine so I did end
up getting life insurance for my little
family and it's weird that's the most
grown-up thing I've ever done a guy came
to my place took my blood in urine asked
me a bunch of questions went away
figured out my likelihood of dying came
back offer me a price I took that bet
and now the only way I can win is to die
they basically come to you and say hey I
bet you won't die in 20 years then you
say
oh I'm serious let's put a half bill on
this let's do it
these are all actual questions from the
life insurance exam do you use tobacco
products no do you on the motorcycle no
do you fly non-commercial jets
No then the pace picks up there's like
30 of these do you go hang gliding no do
you go skydiving
no do you go scuba diving no do you race
cars no to go spelunking no I'm saying
no to everything and in my head I'm like
I'm saving money
the guy leaves and a wave of sadness
hits me I got to get a life
I'm not doing any of the fun stuff so
try to pay attention what's going on the
world and if you saw this scientists
found a drug that reduces obesity and
mice well thank you thank God for that
huh nothing's more embarrassing than
your friends come over and your big fat
mice are all laying around you gonna lie
to your friends I'm sorry you gotta see
this I put a month program you guys told
me we're gonna run in the wheel no we're
doing research on the mice right because
we're good for a drug to make us thin
cuz we all want to be thin we just don't
want to have to eat less or move around
it's so American
we're freaked out about Fitness her dad
I brought down the radio says their
claim it works three times faster than
starvation yeah how do they even know
that it works faster than starvation
have some bizarre clinical trial here's
Mandy sheets three meals a day uses our
product next to her little new boo he's
starving
Melanie booyah give her food early
control group
back on the scale test about our weight
it's crazy
a friend of mine said I'm up 3/4 of a
pound who cares
thought you care about is the number
that's on the scale
try amputation I'm on the new amputation
weight-loss program with one civil
procedure I lost 14 pounds plus now I
can park wherever I want then I am
burning way more calories hopping this
stuff this is true my dad had one leg he
thought that was a funny joke my dad
lost a leg in war-torn Greece when he
was 7 years old and they say what
doesn't kill you makes you stronger that
is not true he was very easy to push
over
I wonder if flamingos ever pissed my dad
off
yeah they got two good legs they stand
there on one seems rude
I later saw the phrase single amputee
and it made me think of my dad and laugh
because I meant it sound like he was
dating or something you know like single
entity seeking woman who likes short
walks you got a laugh right I mean
life's short yeah it doesn't happen
often but once in a while someone will
get mad at something that a comedian
says which has always been weird to me
like if you're with a friend you say
something I'm putting on dude I was just
kidding right like oh you're kidding all
right the tension goes away you're just
kidding this whole thing is I'm just
kidding
that's what this is I was in Pensacola
one night and I said to me surrogate
motherhood is just a really intimate
form of babysitting right like here's
our embryo we'll be back in nine months
a pregnant lady stood up and start
screaming at me she was a surrogate
mother she think that was funny
like well first of all lady I don't care
second of all why are you in a smoky bar
you should be fired from this job
one night Indianapolis I was talking
about a peanut allergy and there's a guy
in the crowd with the peanut allergy
he's mad he threatens to take me to the
alley and beat me up right and I'm very
proud dogs like I don't think so buddy
cuz I might have a Snickers bar
I'm not afraid of you dude you could die
from peanut dust look out there might be
some under my fingernails from the
airplane if I need to I'll get some
Skippy smooth but a visible force still
army buddy you don't know what you gonna
do now be a boy one night Santa Cruz
California basically the joke was don't
beat your wife you think we get all jump
on board with that premise no crazy
troika lady up front this is a direct
quote you don't understand sometimes you
have to let a man work through a phase
[Music]
yeah I've been on the road a long time
it was like drunk women are the
trickiest for a comedian because you
can't tear her apart cuz the crowd
thinks you're being too hard but once in
a while a drunk woman weather up the
show so much that everyone in the room
hates her guts and once that happens you
could say whatever the hell you want
and it totally happened that night she
was just brooding the show at 5:00 told
the guy she was with I was like dude
would you please take her in the parking
lot take care of her so I could finish
up in here I was the King of Comedy for
that minute
and that was fun for me so what's my
point along here be nice to each other
between anything as human beings in life
helps somebody out even if you don't
know the guy right say you're walking
down the street see a parking ticket on
somebody's car take that thing off of
there throw it away right
why should he have to deal with that
headache he won't even have to know
about it
I don't expect everybody to agree with
me about everything I still run to
people once in a while who are against
child labor we've all seen kids bouncing
off the walls at 7:00 in the morning on
a Saturday let them make some Nikes for
a while they learn a trade they make $3
a day in college that's called an
internship you guys see the upside some
of these things like Alzheimer's most of
us spend our whole lives trying to
forget stuff
you gotta let her go you got to forget
about her we've spent our whole lives
trying to forget terrible things that
have happened and finally with
Alzheimer's you're free and how's it the
perfect time nature so beautiful it's
when you're old your body's falling
apart the kids are ignoring live in a
nursing home
imagine how miserably be if you could
remember all that stuff I for one bleed
forward to a time when I can
legitimately answer every question with
I'm a pirate
how come you didn't give me a
Valentine's Day card I'm a pirate you're
clocked out are we thinking the
old-fashioned pirates with the hook and
the eyepatch by the way if you ever get
a hook get yourself an eyepatch you're
gonna get distracted and your eyes gonna
get itchy I think that's why we see
those as a set get enough let it cop
there's gonna be an adjustment period
why do you have a hook on the end of
your stump you're gonna kill yourself
with that thing
is it even useful remember that time
Jimmy saved the day with his hook nope I
can't even think of a thing that you
would use a hook for what are you
delivering ice for a living any noun is
better than a hook a freaking spoon
would be better
pirates gonna have you play once in a
while any noun is better than a hook a
spoon a mechanical pencil a protractor a
garden weasel burn oculars right a hair
curler anything a shot-glass
get a Swiss Army knife then you got some
choices I've got a lot of weird ideas oh
is that the grocery store I'm standing
in front of the grapes I'm thinking
where's the line between sampling and
stealing how many grapes can eat before
somebody freaks out runs over kicks you
out of the store
19 yeah
yeah so you take that as a tip and we
definitely have a zero-tolerance policy
on sampling the canned beverages I
always wonder how many stock boys it
would take the throw me out of the store
what there's another grocery question
for you why do we hunting out of a
plastic bear bears don't make honey well
bears like honey
well bears like salmon I would need
salmon out of a bear I wouldn't you to
put in a little monkey it doesn't make
sense honey in a bear and think of the
message that sends it to our children
hey kids a few squeeze a bear you'll get
a sugary treat kids have to know the
truth do you want a sugary treat you
have to squeeze a B that's called fun
with a four-year-old you buy lemon juice
the store comes in the plastic lemon
that makes sense you buy syrup you think
that would come in a tree Mrs
Butterworth I guess it's the bear rule
she likes syrup I don't know I wouldn't
drink Budweiser out of a big fat guy
yeah I probably would not from Georgia
oh you're doing some braiding found out
Marco Polo as an explorer I thought was
just some guy lost in the pool Marco
Polo right there right kids pool game I
waited in that game after him it was it
lost in the water the game should be
called Amelia Earhart
she's not here Marco Polo's a bad
message for kids anyway I think about
how it's played one kid pretends to be
blind the other kids splash water in his
face and taunt him for not being able to
see it's terrible lot of games you play
that bad mess musical chairs what's the
message there cover your own ass screw
your buddies as we have to take care of
yourself the pinata beat the heck of a
senseless animal of a stick and if
you're really extra violent you'll get
some candy well you all because you have
a blindfold on but your friends will
just another case of the blind guy
getting screwed a lot of bad message for
kids the Tooth Fairy body parts are
worth cash
santa claus sit on a beard strangers lap
tell them your name and where you live
halloween take candy from strangers
if they don't give you any vandalize
their homes this is the worst message
for kids ever to game remember this one
smear the queer that was a game when i
was a boy
now it's a hate crime
remember when Rover and Rover one kid
runs over he breaks through that line he
gets to stay on that side which is
basically our immigration policy
well you did get here
how do you fill of a health picking
fruit
oh that's where you draw the line all
right
I guess football fans NFL fans right yes
yeah what team zero for you guys are
kind of between a few Denver
Philadelphia Chargers Raiders really
alright we got a we got a good mix here
that's nice
alright wait so you you got Broncos
right Broncos Fred
I think the Broncos are a cool story
right Tim Tebow came to that team and
taught them about the power of prayer
and they prayed for a real quarterback
and Peyton Manning came and they won the
Super Bowl it's a nice story meanwhile
Tim Tebow is a good broadcaster right
he's good at something that goes to the
air after all so that's nice Raiders as
you become a Raiders fan you grew up one
really did you are you from there you
just like scary pirates and losing teams
I don't but it's a good call back
points for you sir
it's thought now not everybody remember
this you will JaMarcus Russell was the
number one overall pick for the Raiders
2007 he was the last one to work he was
the first one to leave he was terrible
they paid him 33 million dollars and
they had to cut him and let him go no
one else wanted him people let me say
when they win the lottery they're gonna
quit their jobs
that's what JaMarcus Russell did
you give me 33 mil for every joke I've
written so far you got yourself a deal
buy on how good the jokes are gonna be
after that it's hard to write a joke in
a hammock with a mai tai we're all stay
here and I heard Sea Hawks and there's a
few other okay BYU
you still got Steve Young Steve Young
right am i right it's been a while I'm a
lifelong Falcons fans been a tough run
for me I'm not over that Super Bowl yet
oh God
here's the here's the darkest joke I
ever wrote was that night at least when
you're a Falcons fan then you slit your
wrists you get to die on your own team
colors and won't go away either my
friends Oh a friend of mine calls me he
goes hey man how was your summer on a
scale of 28 to 3
I hate you so much
we got a female ref in the NFL now which
i think is awesome right it's a good
match right
women have been interrupting football
for years
I'm just saying I'm surprised there are
some differences with a female ref right
she throws the flag doesn't tell you why
fifty-five you know female around you
can get a flag for thinking of
committing a penalty
they get in trouble or something he did
three weeks ago and no more instant
replay once she's made up her mind not
interested in the facts
I love football
I missed the redzone channel he has a
it's the best you gotta get it it's
awesome right if you don't know it's one
channel that has all the NFL games
simultaneously no commercials I only
show the teams in the red zone it's so
great I wish they had kiss tacky red
zone where they just show me the
highlights of my own life and cut it all
the crap right I don't need the airports
and the taxicabs I want a room full of
people laughing my kids smile and my
wife getting out of the shower that's it
that's all I I'm a simple man
then occasionally two great things
happen simultaneously they got a double
box at the pizza guy here she dropped
the towel someone's gonna score I'm very
simple all right I got a fortune cookie
I think sums things up nicely for me it
said life is a tragedy for those who
feel and a comedy for those who think
that's true life is really terrible and
it's fantastic it's all in how you look
at it you know take this example guy was
watching the soccer game his wife came
in and changed the channel they got into
a fight he killed her watch the rest of
the game and then called the police
all right that's terrible but I cut that
article out and put it on the
refrigerator and now I can watch
whatever I want
I gotta go guys thank you for the nice
walk
[Applause]
you